<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-01-22T07:23:31+00:00</updated><id>https://rickasikhan.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Era of cinematics</title><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Animation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Era of cinematics"/><published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Animation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Animation/"><![CDATA[<p>With the coming of Unreal Engine 5, Unreal Engine stands out for cinematic productions like Space Marine 2 due to its unmatched real-time rendering capabilities. Unlike Maya and Blender, Unreal Engine allows for rapid iteration and dynamic lighting, providing a level of visual fidelity that is hard to achieve with traditional software. Its Blueprint visual scripting simplifies the integration of interactive elements, while robust virtual cinematography tools make scene choreography seamless. In comparison, Maya and Blender, though powerful in their domains, may require additional steps to match Unreal Engine’s level of interactivity and real-time realism, establishing Unreal Engine as a superior choice for cinematic excellence.</p> <p>However, it’s important to note that while Unreal Engine is primarily designed for games, Maya and Blender have traditionally been tailored for animation and 3D modeling. Maya and Blender excel in providing detailed control over character animation, intricate modeling, and complex simulations, making them preferred choices for many animation and film production pipelines.</p> <p>Unreal Engine’s strength lies in its real-time capabilities and gaming-focused features, making it exceptionally well-suited for creating interactive and immersive experiences. Its cinematic prowess extends beyond games, often chosen for pre-rendered and real-time cinematics due to its advanced rendering and visual effects capabilities.</p> <p>In summary, while Maya and Blender have a strong foundation in animation, Unreal Engine’s versatility allows it to bridge the gap between game development and cinematic production, providing a compelling option for projects like Space Marine 2 that demand both cinematic quality and interactive elements.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/SpaceMarine.jpg" alt="Alt Text" width="800" height="600"/></p> <p>this formula is constantly used by animators to create fluid animations. \(lerp(a,b,t)=a+(b−a)⋅t\)</p> <p>Maya and Blender, leading 3D design software, empower users with scripting capabilities. Maya employs MEL (Maya Embedded Language), while Blender utilizes Python. These scripting languages enable users to automate tasks, create custom tools, and enhance efficiency in modeling, rigging, and animation. The integration of code in both Maya and Blender reflects their adaptability, allowing users to tailor the software to their specific needs and extend functionality beyond default capabilities.</p> <p>an example of mel can be seen here:</p> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-mel" data-lang="mel">// Create a cube in Maya
polyCube;

// Set the cube's translation values
setAttr "pCube1.translateX" 5;
setAttr "pCube1.translateY" 3;
setAttr "pCube1.translateZ" 2;</code></pre></figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="maya"/><category term="Unreal"/><category term="Engine"/><category term="animation"/><category term="3D"/><category term="design"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[cinematics powered by Unreal Engine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Old maya</title><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Maya/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Old maya"/><published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Maya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Maya/"><![CDATA[<p>Autodesk is the company that develops and sells Maya, the 3D computer graphics software. Autodesk is a multinational software corporation that produces a wide range of design and engineering software for various industries, including architecture, engineering, construction, manufacturing, and media and entertainment.</p> <p>Autodesk acquired Maya from Alias Systems Corporation in 2005. Alias Systems Corporation was the original developer of Maya before being purchased by Autodesk. Since then, Autodesk has continued to develop and enhance Maya, making it one of the industry-standard software for 3D animation, modeling, simulation, and rendering.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/Maya.jpg" alt="Alt Text" width="400" height="300"/></p> <p>some commands could only be done via code in the old maya. An example of how the old maya worked:</p> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-mel" data-lang="mel">// Example MEL script to create a bouncing ball animation
int $numFrames = 120;  // Number of frames for the animation
float $bounceHeight = 5.0;  // Height of the bounce
float $bounceFrequency = 0.1;  // Frequency of the bounce

// Create a sphere (ball) in the scene
string $ball = polySphere()[0];

// Keyframe animation for the bouncing ball
for ($frame = 1; $frame &lt;= $numFrames; $frame++) {
    // Calculate the Y position for the bounce using a sine function
    float $yPosition = $bounceHeight * abs(sin($bounceFrequency * $frame));

    // Set the translation of the ball at the current frame
    setKeyframe -at translateY -v $yPosition -t $frame $ball;
}

// Play the animation
playbackOptions -loop "continuous";
playbackOptions -animationStartTime 1 -min 1 -max $numFrames;
playbackOptions -animationEndTime $numFrames -max $numFrames;

playButtonForward;</code></pre></figure> <p>here’s an equation which is frequently used to check whether a certain dynamic is possible or not:</p> \[E = (h^2k^2) / 2m\]]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="maya"/><category term="Alias"/><category term="system"/><category term="corporations"/><category term="Autodesk"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the original developer of maya.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test</title><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Test-Post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test"/><published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Test-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2024/Test-Post/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first text for the first post.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/test.jpg" alt="Alt Text"/></p> \[E = mc^2\] <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">hello</span><span class="p">():</span>
  <span class="nf">print</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">Hello, world!</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="test"/><category term="nothingReally"/><category term=":D"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief introduction to al-folio]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rickasikhan.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>